<resources>
    <string name="instruction_accounts">
        Use the \"Accounts\" tab to work with accounts.\n\n
        Add an account by tapping the \"+\" (or add) button on the bottom of the screen.
        Long tap on an existing account to edit or delete it.\n\n
        Type in the account name (these must be unique) and if desired an account number
         or identifier.\n\n
        Tap on Account Type to see a list of available account types. (This list may be edited,
        but this will impact how accounts are used by the database.)\n\n
        Add other information such as balance, owing, budgeted and credit limit.
        (The budgeted amount is not used by the database and is for your information only.)
    </string>
    <string name="instructions_budget_rules">
        Use the \"Budget Rules\" tab to work with Budget Rules.\n\n
        Add a Budget Rule by tapping the \"+\" (or add) button on the bottom of the screen.
        Long tap on an existing Budget Rule to edit or delete it.\n\n
        Type in the Budget Rule name. (must be unique)\n\n
        Tap to add a \"to\" account and a \"from\" account.
        This will be a default of how a transaction will be performed from the Budget View.
        This may be change when actually performing the transaction.\n
        ie. Instead of a bank account, use a credit card.\n\n
        The amount is the amount budgeted during a pay period or at the time scheduled.
        This may be set to zero just so it appears on the Budget View.\n
        If this is a fixed amount that must be paid you can check \"Fixed amount\".
        This is used to determine which expenses are absolute musts on the Budget.\n\n
        If this rule is a pay day mark it as \"Make a Pay Day\".
        This will schedule the Pay days accordingly.\n\n
        \"Automatic Payment\" is not used at this time.\n\n
        SCHEDULING: \n
        This is the important part of the Budget Rule!\n
        Fill in the start date and do not forget an end date.\n
        Fill in the frequency and the frequency count with a day of week.
        (Note: If weekly is used the day of week is ignored.)\n\n
        The last item is the \"Days Before Due Date\".
        This will move the scheduled date forward to allow for payments to go through,
         or just to notify you in advance of occasional or annual items.\n\n
        Looking at the sample items will familiarize you with what the options are for.\n\n
        NOTE: the actual budget predictions must be updated manually every so often
         as you adjust and fine tune the budget.
         Tap on the menu on the top right and tap \"Update Budget Predictions\" and wait for the
        database to update.
    </string>
    <string name="instructions_budget_view">To fill in the budget,
        you will need to update Budget Rules according to your circumstances.\n\n
        It is important to have a Budget Rule that is a pay day
        to create pay day periods for the budget.\n
        This view will help you to plan where your money will go for each pay period.\n\n
        They can be edited by long tapping on them.
        Most items will have a long tap option.\n
        If you consistently keep track you will see trends that could be changed to
        better use your resources.\n
        Be sure to include annual and occasional expenses so you are not caught by surprise.\n\n
        When you feel your budget rules are correct,
        update budget predictions from the options on the top right to populate this view.
        It is a good idea to \"lock\" items for the current pay period to prevent losing any
        changes you have made.\n\n
        To view a Budget monthly, occasional and annual summary,
        go to the top right menu and choose View Current Budget Summary.
    </string>
    <string name="instructions_transaction_view">Add transactions to discover your spending habits.
        Then you can track your spending on the Analysis view.
        Use this data to update the Budget Rules according to your needs.\n\n
        The key to controlling your spending is to track it and then make realistic budgets.\n\n
        If you add a transaction that will be recurring,
        add a Budget Rule for it to remind you of the next time it comes due.
        </string>
    <string name="instructions_transactions_analysis_view">Add transactions in Budget View or Transaction View.
        Then you can track your spending patterns here.\n\n
        Use this data to update the Budget Rules according to your needs.\n\n
        The key to controlling your spending is to track it and then make realistic budgets. Then
        to monitor your spending throughout the month using the Budget View.\n\n
        </string>
    <string name="instructions_general">The key to using this app is to use it consistently to track
     all your expenses regularly.\n\n
    Step 1. Decide where money is going and coming from - these will be Accounts.
        Go to the Accounts tab at the bottom and rename, add, edit or delete accordingly.
        Long tap on items to view or edit them.\n\n
    Step 2. Figure out as many recurring transactions that will take place.
        ie. Groceries, rent, car loan … etc. Especially you want to create pay days!\n
        Go to the budget rules and rename, add or delete items accordingly.
    Log tap on items to view or edit them.\n
    TIP: View a summary of what the budget looks like by going to the upper right menu
    and choosing \"View Current Budget Summary\".\n\n
    Step 3. Enter transactions as they come along and after a few months you can see an
    analysis of accounts and budget rules. This will help you to fine tune your Budget Rules.\n\n
    Step 4. Regularly look at the Budget View to determine what expenses are scheduled.
        Tap on any item to make a transaction on that item.
        The Budget View will automatically update as you perform transactions so it is
         preferable that you enter transactions from here.
     Check what will come out on future paydays. Notice the surpluses or deficits.
</string>
    <string name="instructions_budget_list">fine tune the current budget
        by going to the options menu on the top right
        and tapping \"View Current Budget Summary\"\n\n
        This gives you a place to view how your monthly income and expenses look.
        Long tapping an item will allow you some options to adjust the budget.\n\n
    </string>
</resources>